Ксардас: Розділ перший
Кай: Де він? Я впевнений, що ми домовилися про плац обміну, але його тут немає.
Кай: Райнхард? РАЙНХАРДЕ?
Кай: Ну добре. Вітаю всіх і ласкаво прошу на...
Кай: Якого біса?!
Райнхард: Я вже тут.
Кай: Нащо, на ім'я Хорініса, ти стрибнув у воду? Ти міг просто зайти через вхід для працівників.
Райнхард: Я знаю, але я люблю цей стрибок.
Кай: І що тепер? Скажеш, що маєш листа для магів вогню?
Рейнхард: Майже. У мене є лист, але він для когось іншого.
Kai: Mmh, fine. So now that you're here, let's start over.
Reinhard: Ready when you are.
Kai: Hi, everyone. And welcome to the""Gothic Remake Behind the Scenes Podcast"".
Reinhard: That's a mouthful. We need a shorter name.
Kai: ""Behind the Gothic Remake Podcast ... thingy"".
Reinhard: That's shorter.
Kai: Oh, look, there's Diego. I was so looking forward to meeting him. Hey, Diego. I'm...
Diego: I'm not interested in who you are. [Well, I...] You've just arrived. I look after the new arrivals. That's all for now.
Reinhard: Thanks, Diego. I'll take care of him. This is Kai Rosenkranz, our composer.
Reinhard: He wrote the soundtrack to the original game more than 20 years ago. Now he's back to do it again for the Gothic 1 remake.
Diego: That's very good for you.
Reinhard: Yeah, He has a crew access pass. I'll show him around.
Kai: Yes, It was about time I get to see the new sets.
Diego: Well then ... you really seem to be an alright guy.
Kai: Thank you. I think I'm... (interrupted)
Diego: Go now! We'll meet in the old camp.
Kai: Yes. Okay.
Kai: Aww, he's such a great guy. And thanks for the introduction, Reinhard. Now, tell everyone who you are.
Reinhard: I am Reinhard Pollice, studio manager and game director at Alkimia Interactive, the studio behind the Gothic 1 remake.
Kai: And you're a diehard Gothic fan and involved in the series for a very long time.
Reinhard: Yes, that's true.
Kai: We'll get back to that. But first, about that shorter name for this podcast. Why don't we just call it the""Gothic Remake Podcast""?
Reinhard: GRP. Sounds good. So welcome to the first episode of the""Gothic Remake Podcast"".
Kai: Yay! Exciting times. We've known each other for what, 15 years now?
Reinhard: Even longer. We first worked together around the launch of Gothic 3 in 2006. Or even earlier than that?
Kai: You worked for JoWooD at that time, right?
Reinhard: Yes!  [ That's... ] I know!
Kai: If I remember correctly, it was you who made this fantastic fan camping during the Games Convention possible. I used to go camping with Gothic fans every year and you helped turning it into a community camping right next to the actually convention center?
Reinhard: Kind of true. But in the end, JoWooD and especially a guy named Ivan Ertlov made it possible. Special shout out to him here.
Kai: Ivan! Yo, my man. What was your job exactly around that time?
Reinhard: It wasn't actually a real job because I was still going to school, but I helped JoWooD with communities, beta tests and supporting games.
Reinhard: Gothic had a sizable and active community team already, so I was mostly working on Spellforce at that time.
Kai: Cool. So now, more than two decades after the release of Gothic 1, we're making a podcast together.
Reinhard: Hold on. (squishy sound)
Kai: Did you just smash a meatbug?
Reinhard: I guess I did.
Kai: Classic. But why are we doing a podcast?
Reinhard: I guess because it makes us two independent. We can just walk around in this beautiful world as it's being built and talk about any aspect of the development process of the game without having to worry about visuals - since this is audio only.
Reinhard: No visual assets need to be finished. Parts of the world can still be under construction. It just doesn't matter.
Kai: Maybe our audience would love to see some work in progress assets.
Reinhard: Oh yeah, absolutely. We'll have those as well: on YouTube, our Discord channel, the Steam page... But for now, this gives us a bit more freedom.
Kai: I love it. We can just walk around, talk, meet people ... [squishy sound] ... crush meatbugs...
Reinhard: Exactly. This episode is about what we think is a good remake. Which aspects we are recreating accurately and where we are adding new content.
Kai: So there will be new content?
Reinhard: Yes. I'm pretty sure you know that since you've already written some new music.
Kai: Oh, yeah. I'm just pointing out that now you officially confirmed it.
Reinhard: It's going to be a very faithful recreation of the original game. The same world, the same beloved characters, the same story, pretty much the same everything.
Reinhard: But we are adding a few things here and there where it just makes sense.
Kai: Like what?
Reinhard: Just wait and see. But I'll give you some good examples.
Reinhard: For example, the original Gothic had some plot holes, open ends, unexplained backgrounds, or even some bigger logic flaws, and we are using those to tie in a few new ideas.
Kai: Whoa, whoa, whoa. What do you mean by""logic flaws""?
Reinhard: Wait, have you been involved in writing of the original story?
Kai: No. No. Only music, sound effects and visual effects. No worries. Go ahead.
Reinhard: Okay. Anyways, there's room for new ideas without changing the original. Just wait and see. [And hear!] Right.
Kai: What's your personal relationship with Gothic? Or in other words, how much of a fan are you?
Reinhard: I played a ton of the original games and I got hooked because of the rough tone. Later, I spent a lot of my time working on mods and learning game development. This way.
Kai: Nice.
Reinhard: And what about you?
Kai: I joined Piranha Bytes when I was 18 in 1998, and I was still at school at that time.
Kai: I had made the decision to try to become a game developer and I was looking for some studios in my area that I could visit and just get an idea of what it's like to be a game developer.
Kai: And then I realized that Piranha Bytes was actually located in my hometown. So I went there and paid them a visit.
Reinhard: The right place at the right time.
Kai: Oh, absolutely. I was so lucky. I visited them at the time when they were still just a handful of people in a tiny office room and some external programmers.
Kai: A few weeks later, I started working on the music for the game and I stayed with Piranha Bytes for 12 years as a composer and sound designer.
Reinhard: Which was the last Piranha Bytes game that you've worked on?
Kai: Risen 1.
Reinhard: And when was the last time you've played actually Gothic one?
Kai: I played it live on Twitch 3 or 4 years ago. But to be honest, I had to rediscover most of the game. There was so much I had forgotten over those past two decades.
Reinhard: Understandably. And if you had to name the most important aspects of Gothic, the defining qualities. Which would you pick? What is the soul, the spirit - whatever you want to call it - of Gothic?
Kai: Wow, that's a big question. Number one, the setting and tone. It's stark, It's gritty, it's violent, it's relentless. And the way it presents a male kind of testosterone filled prison colony really fits for me.
Kai: The tone is harsh and it has a very distinctive flair that is really super important for me. We have to nail this part.
Reinhard: Oh, yeah.
Kai: Voiceovers play a huge role, too.
Reinhard: Definitely.
Kai: Number #2: The living world. The world isn't just a stage for the player. All the creatures and all the NPCs, they just have to behave believably.
Kai: They have to react accordingly to what the player does. And also to what's happening around them. So this whole living, breathing organism of a world, this has to be presented in a in a super believable way.
Kai: And the original Gothic already had that. So we have to try to push it even further.
Reinhard: Yes.
Kai: And the third aspect would be the sense of progression and how it is presented. You start as a nobody, but that doesn't mean that you're a weak character.
Kai: Right from the beginning, the nameless hero is the kind of guy to deal out some soundbites and punches, but still there is this very rewarding sense of progression and the sense of achievement when you get stronger.
Kai: You can even see it in the way you hold your sword and the way you fight. The sense of achievement really matters a lot to me.
Reinhard: Interesting.
Kai: Now your turn. Which aspect would you think are the most important?
Reinhard: I mostly like the living world with its daily routines that not only NPCs have, but also creatures, it really feels alive and reacting.
Reinhard: I also like a lot the ungated experience. The whole world is literally open to you if you have the skill to beat some tough monsters. And of course, I also like the rough tone, the dialogs, the reactions of the nameless hero and the NPCs... It's all well thought out!
Kai: Yeah, I agree.
Reinhard: And now here we are back in this world, walking to the old camp.
Kai: And I got to say, it looks phenomenal. So familiar and so true to the original, but so good! The visual quality is amazing.
Reinhard: It's a podcast, Kai. Audio only!
Kai: I know, but still, if only you all could see this. Look, there's the gate with Orry.
Reinhard: Yes. This part of the world is pretty much complete.
Kai: I love it. What would you say, what percentage of the world is already finished or almost finished?
Reinhard: That's hard to say. There's like a first iteration of everything, except maybe some minor locations. But at this level of detail, I'd say around 50%.
Kai: So still a long way to go.
Reinhard: Yes, but once the workflows and technical aspects are established, it gets a lot faster.
Kai: Did you keep anything from the playable teaser version?
Reinhard: Nothing, except a few raw art assets. We even completely started from a blank Unreal project.
Kai: Okay, before we talk about that, let's go back to the very beginning of the Gothic remake project. It was you who pushed it internally at THQ Nordic, right?
Reinhard: Yes, I was part of this.
Kai: So it is fair to say that we owe this to you, right? Without you, this project wouldn't exist.
Reinhard: No, no, no. I was just...
Kai: Yes, yes, yes. I know this was your passion project, and you were planning to do it for a very long time, waiting for the right opportunity.
Kai: And I just want to say thank you for making this possible. [Reinhard grumbles.] You don't have to respond. That's okay.
Reinhard: There was a few people involved in that process. In the end, a remake felt like a natural step with a series that was dormant for more than ten years.
Kai: How did it all start? Who did you have to convince and how?
Reinhard: Well, we obviously have a process of THQ Nordic about new project, but since we distributed the old Gothic games, we knew very well the potential of those games.
Reinhard: And then one thing led to the other, and we needed a proof of concept for the team making such a production. And so we did the playable teaser.
Kai: Was it your plan from the very beginning to involve the community in the, let's say, design and feedback process?
Reinhard: Not for the playable teaser, but we knew Gothic always had a very strong and opinionated community, and we wanted to make sure they feel part of it.
Kai: Nice. In your opinion, what is a remake in comparison to a remaster or reboot, and what do you think makes a good remake?
Reinhard: That's easily explained. A remake is a full recreation of something existing without deviating too much from the original. A remaster is literally taking the old piece of code and just getting it running on modern systems and doing selective changes.
Kai: And sometimes visual updates. Right?
Reinhard: Exactly. And a reboot is essentially what we did with the playable teaser. So taking the original ideas and just running with it in different directions.
Reinhard: The remake is really a chance to do everything in a modern and future proof way and also extend it where it will provide a lot of value to the game.
Kai: So just to be clear, we're making a remake, right?
Reinhard: Yes, we're making a remake now.
Kai: Oh, hold on. There's that blocked mining tunnel from the original game. And here's... [pickup sound] Tadaa! Our first weapon, A pickaxe.
Reinhard: Right where it used to be.
Kai: Very cool. The tunnel entrance is still blocked. Are you planning to put anything in there or will it stay blocked?
Reinhard: We will all see.
Kai: Ehm, you've mentioned the playable teaser. Can you explain which thoughts went into it and why it turned out the way it did?
Reinhard: The original plan was never to release it. Initially, we wanted to create a proof of concept that this team can work on such a big project.
Reinhard: But then, so much of our own thoughts went into it and it was more a reboot, and we felt the need to either sanity-check it or - like - go back to a safe ground.
Reinhard: In the end, THQ Nordic suggested to release the playable teaser and ask for feedback.
Kai: And then the fan feedback came in.
Reinhard: Yes.
Kai: What was your process of evaluating it and what did you learn from it?
Reinhard: Well, all the feedback came in in a gigantic spreadsheet and we went through all of it. And the most interesting thing was really to see how much different opinions were there about certain details.
Reinhard: But in the end, the good thing was that there was a lot of common ground among the Gothic community.
Kai: So you decided to start from scratch?
Reinhard: Yes, exactly. In the process of making the playable teaser shippable, we took a lot of shortcuts and it just wasn't architected from the start to live on.
Reinhard: We as a team, we never used Unreal before. So we also made some mistakes on how we set up certain things and we just wanted to have a clean slate for the full production and not live with actually a lot of tech depth.
Kai: That's crazy. And just to be clear, when you say Unreal, you mean the Unreal Engine, right?
Reinhard: Yes. We're using the Unreal Engine.
Kai: So how would you answer the following question?""Why should we trust the team that did the playable teaser?""
Reinhard: Because we went through all the feedback and created good action items based on that. We created a vision that is very much in line with what the community wants.
Kai: M-hm.
Reinhard: One second! See that molerat over there?
Kai: Right where it used to be.
Reinhard: Watch. [fighting and squeaking sounds]
Kai: Nice! That looked extremely smooth. Very cool. Is that the new combat system?
Reinhard: Yes. It's based on the Gothic 1 system and it has the same feel to it with instant reactions, different attacks, combos, and kind of the same rhythm.
Reinhard: We've modernized the controls and gameplay to a certain degree, but decided to go a completely different route than in the playable teaser.
Kai: That's very good.
Reinhard: Modernizing the gameplay is the trickiest part, but I think we've got good solutions for all gameplay aspects now.
Kai: Yeah, I'm very curious about this one and also a little worried. But I got to say, everything that I saw so far looks very, very good.
Reinhard: Now we have to leave this part of the podcast to the listeners imagination. But let's talk about an aspect that lends itself perfectly to a podcast.
Kai: Read some source code?
Reinhard: Oh, yeah. No, I mean your music!
Kai: Oh, yeah. As of now, I've already written more than one hour of new music for the Gothic Remake.
Reinhard: Shall we listen to some of it?
Kai: Sure. We're in the middle of nowhere on the path that leads down to the old camp. Let me play some snippets of the music that plays here.
Music: [Music for the path from exchange zone to old camp]
Reinhard: Sweet. So this is definitely based on the original soundtrack.
Kai: Yes. My plan is to follow a""three thirds rule"".
Reinhard: What's that?
Kai: There wasn't a lot of music in Gothic one, and it was repeating and looping a lot. So I am considering this original soundtrack the first of three thirds.
Kai: So the first third is all the original melodies, all the original themes that were in the original game but remastered and modernized so that they sound good in a modern game.
Kai: Then the second set would be variations on these themes. You recognize the material, but there are slight modifications. There are rearrangements and maybe extensions to the original material.
Kai: And then the third third would be completely new music. So there will be tracks for places in the world that didn't have their own music in the original game, and some other things.
Reinhard: That make sense. Can you play a piece to demonstrate that?
Kai: Absolutely. Here's the night version for the music for this area.
Kai: [Night music plays]
Kai: It's the remastered version of the original theme. So the first third.
Kai: And this part is completely new.
Kai: Now, this is the second third based on the same motif.
Reinhard: Oh, wow. Thank you, Kai. That's very interesting.
Kai: Thank you. Is there a similar guideline for the entire game? I mean, do you have a plan as to how much you want to keep 100% accurate and how much you want to add or modify?
Reinhard: I can't come up with a percentage, but the plan is to stay very close where the original shined. So, like the world design, the general mechanics and also the story.
Kai: Very cool. Can we talk a little bit about yourself? [Okay.] Like, what exactly is your role in the Remake's development?
Reinhard: I am the game director and managing director for Alkimia.
Kai: So how much creative influence do you have?
Reinhard: I created the vision for the Gothic remake and all its important features. Now that we are focusing on the implementation details, I make sure to supervise important features and workflows, like, for example, the daily routines.
Kai: What would you say has been your biggest personal influence on the remake?
Reinhard: It's hard to name a few. There's just so many.
Kai: You are originally from Austria, right?
Reinhard: Yes, that's right. So I also speak the original language Gothic was created in.
Kai: And now you're heading a studio in Barcelona. How did you get there? Why Barcelona?
Reinhard: I lived here for a few years and never really had the plan to run a studio here. But then I discovered that there are so many talented game developers here and mostly were just stuck with mobile game studios.
Kai: How did you go about founding a new studio and a new city?
Reinhard: It was an extra challenge because of the pandemic. We started Alkimia in March 2020. I got to know that there are a lot of talented game developers in the city.
Reinhard: So I got to know a core team of five people who I thought were really talented and they were - like - already working together in the past. And so we - just like - throw around ideas what we could work on together.
Reinhard: And so we settled on""let's just start to work on the medieval RPG"", which later became Gothic, and then actually founding the studio was an extra challenge because of the pandemic.
Kai: At that time it was THQ Nordic Barcelona Studio, which then later became Alkimia Interactive, right?
Reinhard: Yes. The plan was never really to stay THQ Nordic Barcelona. It was just our team's name when we needed a team's name for the release of the playable teaser.
Kai: Alkimia Interactive: That's Spanish for alchemy, I guess, right?
Reinhard: Sí señor. But it's actually even cooler. Alkimia is a Basque word, which is a language spoken in the Basque country, which is situated in the north of Spain.
Kai: Aha! How many people are working at Alkimia right now?
Reinhard: We are around 40 people now.
Kai: And how did you come up with that name?
Reinhard: We released the playable teaser as THQ Nordic Barcelona, but after this there was a need to create a unique name - an own identity. So we started to gather names among the team, and in the end it was between two names. And so we chose Alkimia Interactive. And the short form is A.I.
Kai: Uhh, fancy. Is the team going to grow even more?
Reinhard: Yes, we are always looking for talented people.
Kai: And is it easy to get new staff in Barcelona?
Reinhard: Barcelona and Spain, fortunately, has a lot of passionate and talented video game developers. And even better, a lot of them are waiting to work on such a big project for a long time. Here we are, the old camp.
Kai: Wow. Just wow.
Reinhard: Pretty cool, huh?
Kai: Yes. I ... I can't wait to explore it.
Gate Guard: Where do you think you're going? You ain't come to make trouble, have ya?
Kai: No, no, no. I'm a music guy, and I'm going to help build the stage for the concert. I heard you'll be yodeling?
Gate Guard: Hey, this guy's funny. I don't like funny guys. [draws sword]
Reinhard: Wait. Actually, here's our access pass. Also, I have this letter that I have to bring to ... someone!
Gate Guard: Okay. In you go, then.
Kai: And what about me?
Gate Guard: I'll make an exception just this once, 'cause you're new here.
Kai: Thanks, I guess. Oh, Reinhard, you you mentioned a letter. Who is it for?
Reinhard: You will see! ... In another episode of the""GRP"".