Xardas: Kapitola Druhá
Kai: Ahoj, všichni, a vítejte u Gothic Remake Podcastu. Já jsem Kai Rosenkranz, skladatel a zvukový designer.
Reinhard: A já jsem Reinhard Pollice, režisér studia a hry. Vítejte ve starém táboře. Pojďme se projít k aréně.
Kai: Dobrá.
Reinhard: Diego! Oh, wow. Jak se sem dostal tak rychle?
Kai: Znovu tě zdravím, Diego. [Ahoj.] Doufám že se ti líbí nová hudba pro tvůj tábor.
Sprecher 1: Dobrá práce. To není špatné na nováčka.
Kai: Děkuju ti, Diego. Já tenhle tábor tak miluju. Ten šmrnc, nostalgie, ta blátivá vůně.
Reinhard: To je pravděpodobně jen zasedací místnost, ve které nahráváme epizodu.
Kai: Jo, možná. Ale pšššt, narušuješ atmosféru.
Reinhard: Každopádně... Vítejte všichni u druhé epizody o principech designu.
Kai: And by""design principles"" you mean what?
Reinhard: Well, the fundamental principles underneath all of our design choices and ideas. The grand vision, the Ten Commandments that we apply to everything we do.
Kai: Ooh, wow. The very foundation. That's a big subject.
Reinhard: I guess you asked for it.
Kai: Talking about foundations... are these guys over there building the stage? [Yes.] Wait, does that mean concert confirmed?
Reinhard: Well, we can't talk about that right now. We feel like this should be one, though.
Kai: Oh, yes, absolutely. The whole old camp theme was based on""Hermannelig"", an old folk song performed by In Extremo. It would be a blast to have a performance of that song on that stage again.
Reinhard: Absolutely. But let's talk about that another time.
Kai: Okay.
Kai: Why are we going this way? The arena is the other way around the outer ring.
Reinhard: You're absolutely right. But we'll have to pick someone up at the south entrance. And here we have a bit more time to chat before we get there.
Kai: Ah, nice. Are we meeting the person you have to give that letter to?
Reinhard: Well, not right now. We're going to meet Javi Untoria, our lead game designer, at the south entrance. But the letter is not for him.
Kai: Okay, I see. Folks in the outer ring seem to be pretty busy already. Can you talk a little bit about their daily routines and how we're breathing life into this place and its inhabitants? Or would you like to leave that for Javi?
Reinhard: No, no, that's fine. We can talk about it right now. We set out to create a really believable daily schedule, so they will do actions depending on what time of day it is.
Kyle: How often have I told you bastards not to run through my hut?
Reinhard: Sorry, Kyle. We're just...
Kyle: Leave me alone, man. [Alright, we'll just...] Don't build your hut close to the ditch, they said. But none of these bastards told me what would happen if I still did it. When I came back from the mine a few days ago, I had a second door.
Reinhard: And that's exactly what we're going through.
Kyle: Those pigs. I hate them. I can't tell you how much I hate them.
Kai: Uhm... bye, Kyle. I'll see you later.
Sprecher 1: Now everybody runs to my hut.
Kai: Poor guy. [Every idiot.] Shouldn't we move his hut away from the path in the remake?
Reinhard: Ha! Of course not.
Kai: I just hope we won't run into...
Mud: Hey, man, new here? I haven't seen you before.
Kai: Oh, no.
Mud: I'll join you for a while, if you don't mind. I'm sure you'll need a friend.
Kai: Hey, Mud. Sorry, but we're in a little rush. We're g...
Mud: Tell me! Where are we going? Or is it supposed to be a surprise? Hehe, I like surprises.
Reinhard: Mud, you have to go to the stage construction site and help them out, okay? The stage builders said they need your help or they won't be able to finish the stage in time, so.
Mud: So they'll finally understand that they were wrong about me. That'll be fun. [Yeah.] The others only want to get rid of me all the time.
Reinhard: Uhm... yeah. We have to go now, buddy.
Mud: Now I'm going to tell them a few of things. I'll think of a plan.
Kai: Aaaw, that was so nice of you.
Reinhard: Well, I'm gonna have to give the stage builders a massive pay rise.
Kai: I guess so. You said we'll meet Javi by the south entrance, right? [Yep.] Okay. That gives us a few minutes. Some screenshots of the old camp have already been published, and they were received very well. I can confirm that it looks even better when you're strolling around in it. But I have a question about lighting and colors. [Sure.]
Kai: It's good to see everything's less colorful and vivid compared to the Playable Teaser. And also I've noticed that it's not as brightly lit as the screenshots that you've published. To me, when I looked at those screenshots last year, the sunlight looked kind of too brutal and it bleached out most of the colors. But this looks much more balanced.
Kai: The lighting is much smoother and also it preserves some of the colors that were in the old camp, but still maintaining that brownish, dusty vibe.
Reinhard: Yes, we want it to really create this rough and dark atmosphere.
Kai: Mmm. I see.
Reinhard: There he is. Hello, Javi.
Javi: Hey, Reinhard, and hi, Kai.
Kai: Javi, so nice to see you.
Javi: You too. Shall we head to the arena?
Reinhard: Yes, please.
Kai: So you're the lead game designer at Alkimia?
Javi: Yes.
Kai: Wow. Thanks for joining us. What do you do exactly?
Javi: My job is to manage the design and level design team. I am in charge of helping the team to maintain a coherent vision and oversee their work. Also, I design some complex system and coordinate with other teams.
Kai: Cool. Are you getting input or - like - guidance or maybe direction from someone above you? Or do you have the last word on design decisions?
Javi: We have clear guidelines of what Gothic is and what Gothic is not. But in the most controversial issues the game director has the last word.
Kai: And the game director is Reinhard, right?
Javi: Yep, he is.
Javi: Look, there is Huno the blacksmith, preparing his smithy for the remake. Would you like to learn a little bit about forging weapons?
Kai: Absolutely.
Reinhard: Hey, Huno, can you give us a quick presentation of how you go about forging weapons in the remake? Or would that take too long?
Huno: That depends. I'm as fast as a hurricane with simple swords.
Reinhard: Nice. A simple sword will do, thanks. You do your thing and Javi can explain a bit about the new forging mechanics.
Javi: A fantastic thing about Gothic is that you could make your own sword by going through the whole forging process step by step. We will keep that for sure! But we want to take it further, and the player will be able to forge more types of weapons. No, just the simple sword.
Kai: Thank you for the insight, Javi, and thanks, Huno, for your time. Hope we didn't badger you for too long.
Huno: Nah, on the contrary.
Kai: He's always so polite. Just as I remember him. *Laughing* Wow! The arena looks massive. The screenshots already revealed that it got scaled up and extended, but it looks even bigger when you're approaching it.
Javi: Yes. We have expanded the arena and its role in the camp.
Kai: Ah. How exactly?
Javi: Well, the arena is the only way for the colony inhabitants to have fun. We want to give it a more important role, when even the ore barons come out from the castle to watch the fights. [M-hm.] We would like to add more quest and content around the arena, and not just limit ourselves to the few 1 vs.1 fights like in the original.
Javi: For this, we need to expand it and create a focus on the camp. It's still the remains of a building for fighting, but now more people can come and fight. It can't just be limited to some fighters.
Kai: Interesting. So who's going to fight in the arena?
Javi: There are many warriors in the colony who'd like to test their skill, as well as some terrifying creatures that many barons would like to see fight.
Kai: Okay. Wow. That was pretty detailed. Thank you so much.
Javi: You are welcome.
Reinhard: Are you guys hungry? Snaf's crew cantina should be open.
Kai: Good ol' Snaf?
Javi: Sounds good.
Kai: Yeah, it does. Will he serve the original meatbug ragout?
Reinhard: He will in the remake! But for us, he's making a huge paella. The studio is based in Spain, after all.
Javi: Oh, wait. Mud is speaking with Snaf.
Reinhard: Mud? Shouldn't he be on the other side of the camp helping to stage builders?
Kai: I don't know. My gut feeling tells me they sent him away.
Mud: Got something to eat for me? [Here.] Great.
Reinhard: Hey, Snaf.
Snaf: Hey. What'll it be?
Reinhard: Can we have three portions of your paella?
Snaf: Alright. Here! You can try a portion right away.
Kai: I'll take it. Thank you. Mmmmh.
Snaf: What do you think? [That's really good.] Excellent.
Reinhard: Thanks.
Javi: To be clear: Snaf, in the remake, you will be serving your beloved meatbug ragout. Not paella, right? [Exactly.]
Kai: So no changes here. Just mushrooms and meatbugs? [I didn't say that.] Hmm.
Kai: So, Reinhard said, this episode will be about design principles.
Javi: Yes, I heard that, too.
Kai: That sounds like exactly the kind of topic we should ask YOU about, Javi.
Javi: I might know a thing or two about it. Yes.
Kai: Excellent. Elaborate, please. What are the design principles you've established for the remake?
Javi: We have a very clear basis for the game. We will talk about the three main concept.
Kai: M-hm, okay.
Javi: First, the player can choose how to play. We have to give them options and different playstyles.
Reinhard: Oh, yeah.
Kai: Yeah. Sounds good.
Javi: Two: The world is alive. We are not looking for something scripted. We want something systemic that the player can interact with.
Kai: Oh, yes. Very important.
Javi: Yes. And the third pillar is:""Immersion is essential"". We don't want to guide the player with obligatory tutorials, but reward the player to discover and explore the world. We know this can be a little bit harsh at the beginning, but it's the Gothic experience.
Kai: Yes, it is. That's very interesting. So what's your process when you evaluate new design ideas? How do you make sure they match the principles?
Javi: When we design something new or work in our redesign, we always confront it with the pillars as a validation that we are on the right track. In fact, in design, we tend to close the issue with""this is very Gothic"".
Kai: Okay, here's a question very closely related to design principles. I know that the idea that players can just read their stats and skills and get an idea of how good they are just by looking at the character and his posture, that was one of the design concepts Mike Hoge, the original Gothic inventor, was most passionate about. What are your thoughts on this?
Javi: It's something super interesting and something we have all noticed when we were playing Gothic. It's especially something you notice in the hero himself. How he improves with the weapons and goes from barely knowing how to hold a sword to being a true master.
Kai: Oh yes, barely knowing how to hold your sword... I remember that phase. [Yeah.] *laughing* Okay, go ahead.
Javi: It's something that we would like to keep and be able to give this feeling of power and progression.
Kai: Okay. Yeah, that sounds very good. And since you've mentioned progression: Another super important aspect, at least for me, is exactly that sense of progression. Progression of power, to be precise.
Javi: Yes.
Kai: Getting stronger and feeling the impact of that. [Yes.] How is that handled in the remake?
Javi: The progression of power is something that is super important in the game. The character progression in the original Gothic was great. We want to keep the player progression as in the original, but we are refining how the player gets access to better weapons and items, especially in the midgame. It was very easy to break the economy and have the best equipment that money could buy.
Kai: Oh, yeah, that's true. Lovely. Thank you. Can I ask you TWO a few more questions that span across various topics?
Javi: [Okay.] Yes. Let's see if we can answer them.
Kai: I'm sure you can. Javi, where do you draw your inspiration from?
Javi: Inspiration can come from anywhere, not just another video games. Sometimes inspiration come from books, movies, series or even board games and roleplaying games. Often the best ideas come when you least expect them.
Kai: Yes. And what are your favorite games? Are you planning to work some of what you liked about those games into the remake?
Javi: I love action RPGs, but I play as many games as I can. When I play, I cannot stop being a designer and I am constantly analyzing the details and solutions that other devs have found. All these backlogs come to my mind when a new challenge appears in the development, and I think:""These games solved it in a very clever way. We could do something similar!""
Kai: Cool. Yeah. Being open for that definitely helps. You don't always have to reinvent the wheel.
Javi: Yes.
Kai: The next couple of questions are community questions, which came up on the Discord server.
Javi: Oh, nice.
Reinhard: All your listeners out there are invited to join the Discord server as well. The invitation link is discord.gg/gothic.
Kai: See you all there! So ... we've talked about forging. How about making arrows?
Javi: You will be able to make arrows on the workbenches if you have the materials. We want to incorporate crafting to make the materials you collect useful.
Kai: Mm-hmm. Talking about making things useful: In the original game, there are barrels, including here in the old camp, that the player can climb into and hide. Is that going to be a useful mechanic in the remake?
Javi: This mechanic is one of those we revise. In the original it didn't make much sense and it was too comical for the tone of the game. We want to develop stealth a little more, but I don't know if hiding in a barrel is the best way.
Kai: Ooooh *sighs*, okay. Now, we've been to the arena, so this fits quite nicely: A question that came up very often is:""Will there be helmets and shields?""
Javi: No! We are sticking to the original and there won't be any. In the colony the combat is direct and visceral. We didn't like the defence system that will make it more static.
Kai: Yes, I agree. The next one is probably not so much a game design question, but it came up recently, so:""Will there be new quests?""
Javi: Yes, there will be new quests. Our idea is to create quests to balance the parts of the game that feel more linear. As you know, from Chapter 3 onward the game offers no other quest than the main quest.
Kai: Oh yeah.
Javi: And we would like to give more content to the player. On the other hand, some of the main quests will be slightly modified in order to close the plot holes that have been with us for 20 years.
Kai: Very interesting.
Reinhard: When we'll meet with someone from the story team in a future episode, we can dive more into these kind of questions.
Kai: Yeah, that'll be cool. Okay, next. I know this is a broad question, but I want to ask it as openly as possible. What can you tell us about the UI in the remake, and specifically the inventory?
Javi: The UI will look more like the original Gothic than the Playable Teaser. [Yes!] We are doing something minimal to enhance the player immersion. The inventory follows the rules of the original Gothic. The game doesn't pause and allows you to watch as you manage it. It's a screen with a lot of information, so it's a challenge to show everything at once.
Kai: M-hm, it is! Okay, but now for something completely different. We've heard a few characters speaking in this episode, and those were all audio files from the original game. But, Reinhard, we won't use those in the remake, right?
Reinhard: No! We thought initially that's the best way to approach it, but we realized that this wouldn't make any changes or additions possible.
Kai: Which means that we will mostly do rerecordings with the original actors - where it's possible -, right?
Reinhard: Yep.
Kai: Alright. That's good news to me! And which gameplay features and mechanics are we adding that we weren't in the original game?
Javi: We are working on several new features. As a preview, you will now be able to climb some walls in the game. This allows us to reward the more exploratory players and also to develop more vertical levels.
Kai: Uuuh... climbing walls. Nice!
Javi: We have also redesigned pickpocketing, lockpicking, some crafting systems... We have more surprises, but we don't want to reveal them all at once.
Kai: Yeah, that makes sense. We have to keep some for the next episodes.
Reinhard: It's starting to get dark. We've been chatting for quite a while. [Oh, yes.] Kai, how about we end this episode with some music? Night in the old camp, maybe?
Kai: I was hoping for you to ask that. Yeah, I'd love to share some of that.
Reinhard: Okay, then. Do you have any other questions before we wrap this up?
Kai: Yes. About that letter... who is it for? You're making such a big secret out of it.
Reinhard: Oh, yeah, I completely forgot about that. [Sure.] Guess we'll leave that for the next episode, then.
Kai: That's a pretty decent cliffhanger. Anyways, Javi, thank you so much for joining us.
Javi: Thanks for inviting me. I'm looking forward to coming back and talking more about the Gothic remake.
Kai: Yes, that will be great. So, here's a bit of night music from the old camp. See you all in the next episode.
Javi: Bye bye, everybody.
Reinhard: Take care. Bye Bye.
Kai: Thank you for listening. That was... Chapter 2.