Xardas: Capitolo due
Kai: Salve a tutti, e benvenuti al Gothic Remake Podcast. Io sono Kai Rosenkranz, compositore e sound designer.
Reinhard: E io sono Reinhard Pollice, studio e game director. Benvenuti a campo vecchio. Facciamo una passeggiata verso l'arena.
Kai: D'accordo.
Reinhard: Diego! Oh, wow. Come sei arrivato così in fretta?
Kai: Salve di nuovo, Diego [Salve.] Spero ti piaccia la nuova musica per il tuo campo.
Diego: Ottimo lavoro. Non male per un nuovo arrivato.
Kai: Grazie Diego. Amo questo campo. Lo stile, la nostalgia, questo odore fangoso.
Reinhard: Probabilmente quello viene dalla stanza da cui stiamo registrando l'episodio.
Kai: Si, forse. Ma shhh, stai rompendo l'immersione.
Reinhard: Comunque... Benvenuti all'episodio due sui principi di design.
Kai: E per "principi di design" intendi?
Reinhard: Beh, i principi fondamentali alla base delle nostre scelte di design e idee. La visione d'insieme, i Dieci Comandamenti che applichiamo a tutto ciò che facciamo.
Kai: Ooh, wow. Le fondamenta. Un argomento importante.
Reinhard: Immagino sia quello che vuoi.
Kai: A proposito di fondamenta... quei tizi laggiù stanno costruendo un palco? [Sì.] Aspetta, vuol dire che il concerto è confermato?
Reinhard: Beh, non possiamo parlare ora di questo. Pensiamo che dovrebbe essercene uno però.
Kai: Oh, sì, assolutamente. L'intera colonna sonora di campo vecchio era basata su "Herr Mannelig", una vecchia canzone folk suonata dagli In Extremo. Sarebbe fighissimo poter sentire nuovamente un'altra performance su quel palco.
Reinhard: Assolutamente. Ma ne parleremo un'altra volta.
Kai: Va bene.
Kai: Perché prendiamo questa strada? L'arena è dell'altra parte dell'anello.
Reinhard: Hai ragione. Ma dobbiamo andare da qualcuno all'entrata sud. Inoltre qui abbiamo un po' di tempo per chiacchierare prima di arrivare là.
Kai: Ah, bene. Incontreremo la persona a cui devi dare la lettera?
Reinhard: Beh, non ora. All'entrata sud incontreremo Javi Untoria, il nostro lead designer. Ma la lettera non è per lui.
Kai: D'accordo, capisco. Le persone nell'anello esterno sembrano molto indaffarate. Ci puoi parlare un pochino delle loro routine giornaliere e del come respireremo la vita di questo posto e dei suoi abitanti? O vuoi lasciare la risposta a lui?
Reinhard: No, no, non c'è problema. Possiamo parlarne ora. Abbiamo create una lista estremamente credile, quindi compiranno azioni dipendentemente dall'orario del giorno.
Kyle: Quante volte ho detto a voi bastardi di non passare per la mia capanna?
Reinhard: Scusa, Kyle. Stiamo solo...
Kyle: Lasciami in pace. [D'accordo, dobbiamo solo...] Non costruire la casa vicino al fosso, mi dissero. Ma nessuno di quei bastardi mi ha detto cosa sarebbe successo se lo avessi comunque fatto. Quando sono tornato dalla miniera qualche giorno fa, avevo un secondo ingresso.
Reinhard: Ed è esattamente il punto in cui passeremo.
Kyle: Quegli stronzi. Li odio. Non riesco ad esprimere quanto.
Kai: Uhm... arrivederci, Kyle. Ci si vede.
Kyle: Ormai tutti entrano nella mia capanna.
Kai: Poverino [Tutti gli idioti.] Non dovremmo spostare la sua capanna lontano dalla strada nel remake?
Reinhard: Ah! Certo che no.
Kai: Spero solo che non ci imbatteremo in...
Mud: Hey, amico, sei nuovo? Non ti ho mai visto prima.
Kai: Oh, no.
Mud: Mi unirò a te per un po', se non ti dispiace. Sono sicuro che ti serva un amico.
Kai: Hei, Mud. Scusa, ma siamo di fretta. Stiamo and...
Mud: Dimmi! Dove stiamo andando? O è per che caso una sorpresa? Hehe, adoro le sorprese.
Reinhard: Mud, devi andare dove stanno costruendo il palco e dare una mano, d'accordo? I costruttori hanno detto che hanno bisogno del tuo aiuto o non riusciranno a finire il palco in tempo, quindi.
Mud: Quindi finalmente capiranno che si sbagliano su di me. Sarà divertente. [Si.] Gli altri voglio sempre sbarazzarsi di me ogni volta.
Reinhard: Uhm... già. Dobbiamo andare, amico.
Mud: Ora glie ne dirò quattro. Penserò ad un piano.
Kai: Aaaw, è stato gentile da parte tua.
Reinhard: Beh, dovrò dare a quei costruttori un aumento enorme.
Kai: Immagino. Hai detto che avremmo incontrato Javi all'entrata sud, corretto? [Sì.] D'accordo. Questo ci dà qualche minuto. Alcuni screenshots di campo vecchio sono già stati pubblicati, e sono stati apprezzati molto. Posso confermare che sembra ancora meglio quando ci passeggi dentro. Ma ho una domanda per quanto riguarda luci e colori. [Certo.]
Kai: È bello vedere tutto meno colorato e vivido rispetto al teaser giocabile. Ho anche notato che non è così luminoso come negli screenshots che avete pubblicato. Personalmente, quando ho visto quegli screenshot l'anno scorso, sembrava che il sole fosse così forte da sbiancare la maggior parte dei colori. Ma qui sembra tutto più bilanciato.
Kai: La luminosità è molto più morbida e mantiene alcuni colori che si trovavano a campo vecchio, ma sempre mantenendo quel tono marroncino e polveroso.
Reinhard: Si, vogliamo assicurarci di creare un'atmosfera dura e cupa.
Kai: Mmm. Capisco.
Reinhard: Ed eccolo qui. Ciao, Javi.
Javi: Ciao, Reinhard, e ciao Kai.
Kai: Javi, che piacere vederti.
Javi: Anche a te. Ci dirigiamo all'arena?
Reinhard: Si, per favore.
Kai: Quindi sei il lead designer in Alkimia?
Javi: Si.
Kai: Wow. Grazie per esserti unito a noi. Cosa fai esattamente?
Javi: Il mio lavoro consiste nel dirigere i team di design e level design. Ho il compito di aiutare il team a mantenere una visione coerente e supervisionare il loro lavoro. Inoltre, progetto alcuni sistemi complessi e coordino con gli altri team.
Kai: Fico. Ricevi un input o -tipo- una guida o magari una direzione da qualcuno sopra di te? O hai l'ultima parola sulle decisioni di design?
Javi: Abbiamo delle linee guida chiare sul cosa sia e non sia Gothic. Ma nei problemi più controversi il game director ha l'ultima parola.
Kai: E il game director è Reinhard, giusto?
Javi: Si, lo è.
Javi: Guarda, c'è Huno il fabbro, e sta preparando i suoi attrezzi per il remake. Ti piacerebbe sapere qualcosa riguardo il creare armi?
Kai: Assolutamente.
Reinhard: Hei, Huno, potresti darci una veloce presentazioni di come creerai armi nel remake? O ci vorrebbe troppo tempo?
Huno: Dipende. Sono veloce come un uragano con le parole semplici.
Reinhard: Ottimo. Una spada semplice andrà bene, grazie. Tu fai pure e Javi spiegherà un pochino le nuove meccaniche di forgiatura.
Javi: Una cosa fantastica di Gothic è che puoi creare la tua spada attraverso tutto il processo di forgiatura passo per passo. Lo manterremo di certo! Ma vogliamo fare di più, e il giocatore sarà in grado di creare più tipologie di armi, non solo la semplice spada.
Kai: Grazie per l'informazione, Javi, e grazie, Huno per averci dedicato del tempo. Speriamo di non averti tormentato troppo.
Huno: Nah, al contrario.
Kai: È sempre così educato. Proprio come me lo ricordavo. *Ride* Wow! L'arena sembra gigantesca. Le immagini mostravano già che fosse stata ingrandita ed estesa, ma sembra ancora più grande da vicino.
Javi: Si. Abbiamo ingrandito l'arena e il suo ruolo nel campo.
Kai: Ah. Come esattamente?
Javi: Beh, l'arena è l'unico svago per gli abitanti della colonia. Volevamo dargli un ruolo più importante, dato che perfino i baroni del metallo escono dal castello per guardare i combattimento. [M-hm.] Ci piacerebbe aggiungere più missioni e contenuti attorno all'arena, e non solo limitarci ad alcuni scontri 1 v 1 come nell'originale.
Javi: Perciò, dobbiamo espanderla e creare un punto centrale nell'accampamento. Sono ancora i resti di un edificio per i combattimenti, ma ora più persone potranno entrare e combattere. Non può essere limitata ad alcuni combattenti.
Kai: Interessante. Quindi chi combatterà nell'arena?
Javi: Ci sono così tanti guerrieri nella colonia che vogliono testare le proprie capacità, così come alcune terrificanti creature che molti baroni vorrebbero vedere combattere.
Kai: Ok. Wow. È stato molto dettagliato. Grazie mille.
Javi: Prego.
Reinhard: Avete fame? La cantina della brigata di Snaf dovrebbe essere aperta.
Kai: Il buon vecchio Snaf?
Javi: Per me va bene.
Kai: Si assolutamente. Servirà l'originale stufato di scarafaggio?
Reinhard: Lo farà nel rremake! Ma per noi, sta preparando una gigantesca paella. Lo studio è in Spagna dopotutto.
Javi: Oh, aspetta. Mud sta parlando con Snaf.
Reinhard: Mud? Non dovrebbe essere dall'altro lato del campo aiutando gli operai?
Kai: Non lo so. Il mio stomaco mi dice che lo hanno mandato via.
Mud: Hai qualcosa da mangiare per me? [Tieni.] Grandioso.
Reinhard: Hei, Snaf.
Snaf: Hei. Cosa volete?
Reinhard: Potremmo avere tre porzioni di paella?
Snaf: D'accordo. Tieni! Puoi provarne un po' subito.
Kai: La prendo io. Grazie. Mmmmh.
Snaf: Che ne pensi?? [È molto buona.] Eccellente.
Reinhard: Grazie.
Javi: Per essere chiari: Snaf, nel remake, servirai il tuo amato stufato di scarafaggio. Non la paella, giusto? [Esattamente.]
Kai: Quindi nessun cambiamento. Solo funghi e scarafaggi? [Non ho detto questo.] Hmm.
Kai: Allora, Reinhard ha detto che questo episodio sarà incentrato sui principi del design.
Javi: Si, l'ho sentito anch'io.
Kai: That sounds like exactly the kind of topic we should ask YOU about, Javi.
Javi: I might know a thing or two about it. Yes.
Kai: Excellent. Elaborate, please. What are the design principles you've established for the remake?
Javi: We have a very clear basis for the game. We will talk about the three main concept.
Kai: M-hm, okay.
Javi: First, the player can choose how to play. We have to give them options and different playstyles.
Reinhard: Oh, yeah.
Kai: Yeah. Sounds good.
Javi: Two: The world is alive. We are not looking for something scripted. We want something systemic that the player can interact with.
Kai: Oh, yes. Very important.
Javi: Yes. And the third pillar is:""Immersion is essential"". We don't want to guide the player with obligatory tutorials, but reward the player to discover and explore the world. We know this can be a little bit harsh at the beginning, but it's the Gothic experience.
Kai: Yes, it is. That's very interesting. So what's your process when you evaluate new design ideas? How do you make sure they match the principles?
Javi: When we design something new or work in our redesign, we always confront it with the pillars as a validation that we are on the right track. In fact, in design, we tend to close the issue with""this is very Gothic"".
Kai: Okay, here's a question very closely related to design principles. I know that the idea that players can just read their stats and skills and get an idea of how good they are just by looking at the character and his posture, that was one of the design concepts Mike Hoge, the original Gothic inventor, was most passionate about. What are your thoughts on this?
Javi: It's something super interesting and something we have all noticed when we were playing Gothic. It's especially something you notice in the hero himself. How he improves with the weapons and goes from barely knowing how to hold a sword to being a true master.
Kai: Oh yes, barely knowing how to hold your sword... I remember that phase. [Yeah.] *laughing* Okay, go ahead.
Javi: It's something that we would like to keep and be able to give this feeling of power and progression.
Kai: Okay. Yeah, that sounds very good. And since you've mentioned progression: Another super important aspect, at least for me, is exactly that sense of progression. Progression of power, to be precise.
Javi: Yes.
Kai: Getting stronger and feeling the impact of that. [Yes.] How is that handled in the remake?
Javi: The progression of power is something that is super important in the game. The character progression in the original Gothic was great. We want to keep the player progression as in the original, but we are refining how the player gets access to better weapons and items, especially in the midgame. It was very easy to break the economy and have the best equipment that money could buy.
Kai: Oh, yeah, that's true. Lovely. Thank you. Can I ask you TWO a few more questions that span across various topics?
Javi: [Okay.] Yes. Let's see if we can answer them.
Kai: I'm sure you can. Javi, where do you draw your inspiration from?
Javi: Inspiration can come from anywhere, not just another video games. Sometimes inspiration come from books, movies, series or even board games and roleplaying games. Often the best ideas come when you least expect them.
Kai: Yes. And what are your favorite games? Are you planning to work some of what you liked about those games into the remake?
Javi: I love action RPGs, but I play as many games as I can. When I play, I cannot stop being a designer and I am constantly analyzing the details and solutions that other devs have found. All these backlogs come to my mind when a new challenge appears in the development, and I think:""These games solved it in a very clever way. We could do something similar!""
Kai: Cool. Yeah. Being open for that definitely helps. You don't always have to reinvent the wheel.
Javi: Yes.
Kai: The next couple of questions are community questions, which came up on the Discord server.
Javi: Oh, nice.
Reinhard: All your listeners out there are invited to join the Discord server as well. The invitation link is discord.gg/gothic.
Kai: See you all there! So ... we've talked about forging. How about making arrows?
Javi: You will be able to make arrows on the workbenches if you have the materials. We want to incorporate crafting to make the materials you collect useful.
Kai: Mm-hmm. Talking about making things useful: In the original game, there are barrels, including here in the old camp, that the player can climb into and hide. Is that going to be a useful mechanic in the remake?
Javi: This mechanic is one of those we revise. In the original it didn't make much sense and it was too comical for the tone of the game. We want to develop stealth a little more, but I don't know if hiding in a barrel is the best way.
Kai: Ooooh *sighs*, okay. Now, we've been to the arena, so this fits quite nicely: A question that came up very often is:""Will there be helmets and shields?""
Javi: No! We are sticking to the original and there won't be any. In the colony the combat is direct and visceral. We didn't like the defence system that will make it more static.
Kai: Yes, I agree. The next one is probably not so much a game design question, but it came up recently, so:""Will there be new quests?""
Javi: Yes, there will be new quests. Our idea is to create quests to balance the parts of the game that feel more linear. As you know, from Chapter 3 onward the game offers no other quest than the main quest.
Kai: Oh yeah.
Javi: And we would like to give more content to the player. On the other hand, some of the main quests will be slightly modified in order to close the plot holes that have been with us for 20 years.
Kai: Very interesting.
Reinhard: When we'll meet with someone from the story team in a future episode, we can dive more into these kind of questions.
Kai: Yeah, that'll be cool. Okay, next. I know this is a broad question, but I want to ask it as openly as possible. What can you tell us about the UI in the remake, and specifically the inventory?
Javi: The UI will look more like the original Gothic than the Playable Teaser. [Yes!] We are doing something minimal to enhance the player immersion. The inventory follows the rules of the original Gothic. The game doesn't pause and allows you to watch as you manage it. It's a screen with a lot of information, so it's a challenge to show everything at once.
Kai: M-hm, it is! Okay, but now for something completely different. We've heard a few characters speaking in this episode, and those were all audio files from the original game. But, Reinhard, we won't use those in the remake, right?
Reinhard: No! We thought initially that's the best way to approach it, but we realized that this wouldn't make any changes or additions possible.
Kai: Which means that we will mostly do rerecordings with the original actors - where it's possible -, right?
Reinhard: Yep.
Kai: Alright. That's good news to me! And which gameplay features and mechanics are we adding that we weren't in the original game?
Javi: We are working on several new features. As a preview, you will now be able to climb some walls in the game. This allows us to reward the more exploratory players and also to develop more vertical levels.
Kai: Uuuh... climbing walls. Nice!
Javi: We have also redesigned pickpocketing, lockpicking, some crafting systems... We have more surprises, but we don't want to reveal them all at once.
Kai: Yeah, that makes sense. We have to keep some for the next episodes.
Reinhard: It's starting to get dark. We've been chatting for quite a while. [Oh, yes.] Kai, how about we end this episode with some music? Night in the old camp, maybe?
Kai: I was hoping for you to ask that. Yeah, I'd love to share some of that.
Reinhard: Okay, then. Do you have any other questions before we wrap this up?
Kai: Yes. About that letter... who is it for? You're making such a big secret out of it.
Reinhard: Oh, yeah, I completely forgot about that. [Sure.] Guess we'll leave that for the next episode, then.
Kai: That's a pretty decent cliffhanger. Anyways, Javi, thank you so much for joining us.
Javi: Thanks for inviting me. I'm looking forward to coming back and talking more about the Gothic remake.
Kai: Yes, that will be great. So, here's a bit of night music from the old camp. See you all in the next episode.
Javi: Bye bye, everybody.
Reinhard: Take care. Bye Bye.
Kai: Thank you for listening. That was... Chapter 2.