Xardas: Capitolul doi
Kai: Salutare tuturor și bine ați venit la Gothic Remake Podcast. Eu sunt Kai Rosenkranz, compozitor și designer de sunet.
Reinhard: Iar eu sunt Reinhard Pollice, director de studio și de joc. Bine ați venit în tabăra veche. Să facem o plimbare până la arenă.
Kai: În regulă.
Reinhard: Diego! O, uau. Cum a ajuns aici atât de repede?
Kai: Bună din nou, Diego. [Salut.] Sper că îți place noua muzică pentru tabăra ta.
Diego: Bine lucrat. Nu e rău deloc pentru un nou venit.
Kai: Mulțumesc, Diego. Iubesc atât de mult această tabără. Stilul, nostalgia, mirosul ăsta de noroi.
Reinhard: Probabil că e vorba doar de sala de ședințe în care înregistrăm episodul.
Kai: Da, poate. Dar, șșșt, distrugi imersiunea.
Reinhard: Oricum... Bun venit tuturor la episodul doi despre principiile de design.
Kai: Și ce vrei să spui prin „principii de design”?
Reinhard: Ei bine, principiile fundamentale care stau la baza tuturor alegerilor și ideilor noastre de design. Marea viziune, cele zece porunci pe care le aplicăm în tot ceea ce facem.
Kai: O, uau. Fundația însăși. E un subiect important.
Reinhard: Cred că tu ai cerut asta.
Kai: Apropo de fundații... tipii ăștia de acolo construiesc scena? [Da.] Stai, asta înseamnă că s-a confirmat concertul?
Reinhard: Ei bine, nu putem vorbi despre asta acum. Totuși, credem că ar trebui să existe unul.
Kai: O, da, absolut. Întreaga melodie a taberei vechi s-a bazat pe „Herr Mannelig”, un vechi cântec popular interpretat de In Extremo. Ar fi genial să avem din nou o interpretare a acelui cântec pe acea scenă.
Reinhard: Absolut. Dar să vorbim despre asta altă dată.
Kai: Bine.
Kai: De ce mergem pe aici? Arena este în partea cealaltă a inelului exterior.
Reinhard: Ai perfectă dreptate. Dar va trebui să luăm pe cineva de la intrarea sudică. Și pe aici avem ceva mai mult timp să discutăm înainte de a ajunge acolo.
Kai: A, drăguț. O să ne întâlnim cu persoana căreia trebuie să-i dai scrisoarea?
Reinhard: Ei bine, nu chiar acum. Ne vom întâlni cu Javi Untoria, game designerul nostru principal, la intrarea sudică. Dar scrisoarea nu e pentru el.
Kai: Bine, înțeleg. Oamenii din inelul exterior par să fie deja destul de ocupați. Poți să ne vorbești puțin despre rutina lor zilnică și despre modul în care dăm viață acestui loc și locuitorilor săi? Sau vrei să lași asta lui Javi?
Reinhard: Nu, nu, e în regulă. Putem vorbi despre asta chiar acum. Ne-am propus să creăm un program zilnic foarte credibil, astfel încât să facă acțiuni în funcție de ora din zi.
Kyle: De câte ori v-am spus, ticăloșilor, să nu treceți prin coliba mea?
Reinhard: Scuze, Kyle. Noi doar...
Kyle: Lasă-mă în pace, omule. [Bine, o să...] Nu-ți construi coliba aproape de șanț, mi-au spus ei. Dar niciunul dintre nenorociții ăștia nu mi-a spus ce se va întâmpla dacă totuși o voi face. Când m-am întors de la mină, acum câteva zile, m-am trezit cu o a doua ușă.
Reinhard: Și exact prin asta trecem și noi.
Kyle: Porcii ăia. Îi urăsc. Nu pot să vă spun cât de mult îi urăsc.
Kai: Ăăă... pa, Kyle. Ne vedem mai târziu.
Kyle: Acum toată lumea trece prin coliba mea.
Kai: Săracul de el. [Toți idioții.] N-ar trebui să-i mutăm coliba departe de drum în remake?
Reinhard: Ha! Bineînțeles că nu.
Kai: Sper doar să nu dăm peste...
Mud: Hei, omule, ești nou pe aici? Nu te-am mai văzut până acum.
Kai: O, nu.
Mud: Mă voi alătura vouă pentru o vreme, dacă nu vă supărați. Sunt sigur că veți avea nevoie de un prieten.
Kai: Hei, Mud. Scuze, dar suntem puțin grăbiți. Mergem...
Mud: Spune-mi! Unde mergem? Sau ar trebui să fie o surpriză? Hehe, îmi plac surprizele.
Reinhard: Mud, trebuie să te duci pe șantierul de construcție a scenei și să-i ajuți, bine? Constructorii scenei au spus că au nevoie de ajutorul tău, altfel nu vor putea termina scena la timp, așa că...
Mud: Deci vor înțelege în sfârșit că s-au înșelat în privința mea. Asta va fi distractiv. [Da.] Ceilalți vor doar să scape de mine tot timpul.
Reinhard: Ăăă... da. Trebuie să plecăm acum, amice.
Mud: Acum am să le spun câteva lucruri. O să mă gândesc la un plan.
Kai: O, ce drăguț din partea ta.
Reinhard: Ei bine, o să le dau constructorilor de scenă o mărire masivă de salariu.
Kai: Cred că da. Ai spus că ne vom întâlni cu Javi la intrarea din sud, nu? [Da.] Bine. Asta ne dă câteva minute. Câteva capturi de ecran din tabăra veche au fost deja publicate și au fost primite foarte bine. Pot să confirm că arată și mai bine când te plimbi în ea. Dar am o întrebare legată de iluminare și culori. [Sigur.]
Kai: Este îmbucurător să văd că totul este mai puțin colorat și mai puțin intens față de Playable Teaser. De asemenea, am observat că nu este la fel de luminos ca în capturile de ecran pe care le-ați publicat. Pentru mine, când m-am uitat la acele capturi de ecran de anul trecut, lumina soarelui părea cam prea brutală și decolora majoritatea culorilor. Dar asta arată mult mai echilibrat.
Kai: Iluminarea este mult mai fină și, de asemenea, păstrează unele dintre culorile care erau în tabăra veche, păstrând totuși acea notă maronie, prăfuită.
Reinhard: Da, vrem să creeze cu adevărat atmosfera asta dură și întunecată.
Kai: Mmm. Înțeleg.
Reinhard: Iată-l. Bună, Javi.
Javi: Bună, Reinhard, și bună, Kai.
Kai: Javi, ce mă bucur să te văd.
Javi: La fel. Ne îndreptăm spre arenă?
Reinhard: Da, te rog.
Kai: Deci tu ești game designerul principal la Alkimia?
Javi: Da.
Kai: Wow. Mulțumim că ni te-ai alăturat. Cu ce te ocupi mai exact?
Javi: Treaba mea este să gestionez echipa de design și design de nivel. Sunt responsabil să ajut echipa să mențină o viziune coerentă și să le supraveghez activitatea. De asemenea, concep unele sisteme complexe și mă coordonez cu alte echipe.
Kai: Mișto. Primești informații sau - cum ar fi - îndrumări sau poate direcții de la cineva de mai sus? Sau tu ai ultimul cuvânt în ceea ce privește deciziile de design?
Javi: Avem principii clare cu privire la ceea ce este Gothic și ceea ce nu este Gothic. Dar la cele mai controversate subiecte, directorul de joc are ultimul cuvânt.
Kai: Și directorul de joc este Reinhard, nu-i așa?
Javi: Da, el e.
Javi: Priviți, iată-l pe Huno, fierarul, pregătindu-și fierăria pentru remake. Ați vrea să aflați câte ceva despre forjarea armelor?
Kai: Absolut.
Reinhard: Hei, Huno, poți să ne faci o scurtă prezentare a modului în care te ocupi de forjarea armelor în remake? Sau ar dura prea mult?
Huno: Depinde. Mă mișc rapid ca un uragan cu săbiile simple.
Reinhard: Nice. A simple sword will do, thanks. You do your thing and Javi can explain a bit about the new forging mechanics.
Javi: A fantastic thing about Gothic is that you could make your own sword by going through the whole forging process step by step. We will keep that for sure! But we want to take it further, and the player will be able to forge more types of weapons. No, just the simple sword.
Kai: Thank you for the insight, Javi, and thanks, Huno, for your time. Hope we didn't badger you for too long.
Huno: Nah, on the contrary.
Kai: He's always so polite. Just as I remember him. *Laughing* Wow! The arena looks massive. The screenshots already revealed that it got scaled up and extended, but it looks even bigger when you're approaching it.
Javi: Yes. We have expanded the arena and its role in the camp.
Kai: Ah. How exactly?
Javi: Well, the arena is the only way for the colony inhabitants to have fun. We want to give it a more important role, when even the ore barons come out from the castle to watch the fights. [M-hm.] We would like to add more quest and content around the arena, and not just limit ourselves to the few 1 vs.1 fights like in the original.
Javi: For this, we need to expand it and create a focus on the camp. It's still the remains of a building for fighting, but now more people can come and fight. It can't just be limited to some fighters.
Kai: Interesting. So who's going to fight in the arena?
Javi: There are many warriors in the colony who'd like to test their skill, as well as some terrifying creatures that many barons would like to see fight.
Kai: Okay. Wow. That was pretty detailed. Thank you so much.
Javi: You are welcome.
Reinhard: Are you guys hungry? Snaf's crew cantina should be open.
Kai: Good ol' Snaf?
Javi: Sounds good.
Kai: Yeah, it does. Will he serve the original meatbug ragout?
Reinhard: He will in the remake! But for us, he's making a huge paella. The studio is based in Spain, after all.
Javi: Oh, wait. Mud is speaking with Snaf.
Reinhard: Mud? Shouldn't he be on the other side of the camp helping to stage builders?
Kai: I don't know. My gut feeling tells me they sent him away.
Mud: Got something to eat for me? [Here.] Great.
Reinhard: Hey, Snaf.
Snaf: Hey. What'll it be?
Reinhard: Can we have three portions of your paella?
Snaf: Alright. Here! You can try a portion right away.
Kai: I'll take it. Thank you. Mmmmh.
Snaf: What do you think? [That's really good.] Excellent.
Reinhard: Thanks.
Javi: To be clear: Snaf, in the remake, you will be serving your beloved meatbug ragout. Not paella, right? [Exactly.]
Kai: So no changes here. Just mushrooms and meatbugs? [I didn't say that.] Hmm.
Kai: So, Reinhard said, this episode will be about design principles.
Javi: Yes, I heard that, too.
Kai: That sounds like exactly the kind of topic we should ask YOU about, Javi.
Javi: I might know a thing or two about it. Yes.
Kai: Excellent. Elaborate, please. What are the design principles you've established for the remake?
Javi: We have a very clear basis for the game. We will talk about the three main concept.
Kai: M-hm, okay.
Javi: First, the player can choose how to play. We have to give them options and different playstyles.
Reinhard: Oh, yeah.
Kai: Yeah. Sounds good.
Javi: Two: The world is alive. We are not looking for something scripted. We want something systemic that the player can interact with.
Kai: Oh, yes. Very important.
Javi: Yes. And the third pillar is:""Immersion is essential"". We don't want to guide the player with obligatory tutorials, but reward the player to discover and explore the world. We know this can be a little bit harsh at the beginning, but it's the Gothic experience.
Kai: Yes, it is. That's very interesting. So what's your process when you evaluate new design ideas? How do you make sure they match the principles?
Javi: When we design something new or work in our redesign, we always confront it with the pillars as a validation that we are on the right track. In fact, in design, we tend to close the issue with""this is very Gothic"".
Kai: Okay, here's a question very closely related to design principles. I know that the idea that players can just read their stats and skills and get an idea of how good they are just by looking at the character and his posture, that was one of the design concepts Mike Hoge, the original Gothic inventor, was most passionate about. What are your thoughts on this?
Javi: It's something super interesting and something we have all noticed when we were playing Gothic. It's especially something you notice in the hero himself. How he improves with the weapons and goes from barely knowing how to hold a sword to being a true master.
Kai: Oh yes, barely knowing how to hold your sword... I remember that phase. [Yeah.] *laughing* Okay, go ahead.
Javi: It's something that we would like to keep and be able to give this feeling of power and progression.
Kai: Okay. Yeah, that sounds very good. And since you've mentioned progression: Another super important aspect, at least for me, is exactly that sense of progression. Progression of power, to be precise.
Javi: Yes.
Kai: Getting stronger and feeling the impact of that. [Yes.] How is that handled in the remake?
Javi: The progression of power is something that is super important in the game. The character progression in the original Gothic was great. We want to keep the player progression as in the original, but we are refining how the player gets access to better weapons and items, especially in the midgame. It was very easy to break the economy and have the best equipment that money could buy.
Kai: Oh, yeah, that's true. Lovely. Thank you. Can I ask you TWO a few more questions that span across various topics?
Javi: [Okay.] Yes. Let's see if we can answer them.
Kai: I'm sure you can. Javi, where do you draw your inspiration from?
Javi: Inspiration can come from anywhere, not just another video games. Sometimes inspiration come from books, movies, series or even board games and roleplaying games. Often the best ideas come when you least expect them.
Kai: Yes. And what are your favorite games? Are you planning to work some of what you liked about those games into the remake?
Javi: I love action RPGs, but I play as many games as I can. When I play, I cannot stop being a designer and I am constantly analyzing the details and solutions that other devs have found. All these backlogs come to my mind when a new challenge appears in the development, and I think:""These games solved it in a very clever way. We could do something similar!""
Kai: Cool. Yeah. Being open for that definitely helps. You don't always have to reinvent the wheel.
Javi: Yes.
Kai: The next couple of questions are community questions, which came up on the Discord server.
Javi: Oh, nice.
Reinhard: All your listeners out there are invited to join the Discord server as well. The invitation link is discord.gg/gothic.
Kai: See you all there! So ... we've talked about forging. How about making arrows?
Javi: You will be able to make arrows on the workbenches if you have the materials. We want to incorporate crafting to make the materials you collect useful.
Kai: Mm-hmm. Talking about making things useful: In the original game, there are barrels, including here in the old camp, that the player can climb into and hide. Is that going to be a useful mechanic in the remake?
Javi: This mechanic is one of those we revise. In the original it didn't make much sense and it was too comical for the tone of the game. We want to develop stealth a little more, but I don't know if hiding in a barrel is the best way.
Kai: Ooooh *sighs*, okay. Now, we've been to the arena, so this fits quite nicely: A question that came up very often is:""Will there be helmets and shields?""
Javi: No! We are sticking to the original and there won't be any. In the colony the combat is direct and visceral. We didn't like the defence system that will make it more static.
Kai: Yes, I agree. The next one is probably not so much a game design question, but it came up recently, so:""Will there be new quests?""
Javi: Yes, there will be new quests. Our idea is to create quests to balance the parts of the game that feel more linear. As you know, from Chapter 3 onward the game offers no other quest than the main quest.
Kai: Oh yeah.
Javi: And we would like to give more content to the player. On the other hand, some of the main quests will be slightly modified in order to close the plot holes that have been with us for 20 years.
Kai: Very interesting.
Reinhard: When we'll meet with someone from the story team in a future episode, we can dive more into these kind of questions.
Kai: Yeah, that'll be cool. Okay, next. I know this is a broad question, but I want to ask it as openly as possible. What can you tell us about the UI in the remake, and specifically the inventory?
Javi: The UI will look more like the original Gothic than the Playable Teaser. [Yes!] We are doing something minimal to enhance the player immersion. The inventory follows the rules of the original Gothic. The game doesn't pause and allows you to watch as you manage it. It's a screen with a lot of information, so it's a challenge to show everything at once.
Kai: M-hm, it is! Okay, but now for something completely different. We've heard a few characters speaking in this episode, and those were all audio files from the original game. But, Reinhard, we won't use those in the remake, right?
Reinhard: No! We thought initially that's the best way to approach it, but we realized that this wouldn't make any changes or additions possible.
Kai: Which means that we will mostly do rerecordings with the original actors - where it's possible -, right?
Reinhard: Yep.
Kai: Alright. That's good news to me! And which gameplay features and mechanics are we adding that we weren't in the original game?
Javi: We are working on several new features. As a preview, you will now be able to climb some walls in the game. This allows us to reward the more exploratory players and also to develop more vertical levels.
Kai: Uuuh... climbing walls. Nice!
Javi: We have also redesigned pickpocketing, lockpicking, some crafting systems... We have more surprises, but we don't want to reveal them all at once.
Kai: Yeah, that makes sense. We have to keep some for the next episodes.
Reinhard: It's starting to get dark. We've been chatting for quite a while. [Oh, yes.] Kai, how about we end this episode with some music? Night in the old camp, maybe?
Kai: I was hoping for you to ask that. Yeah, I'd love to share some of that.
Reinhard: Okay, then. Do you have any other questions before we wrap this up?
Kai: Yes. About that letter... who is it for? You're making such a big secret out of it.
Reinhard: Oh, yeah, I completely forgot about that. [Sure.] Guess we'll leave that for the next episode, then.
Kai: That's a pretty decent cliffhanger. Anyways, Javi, thank you so much for joining us.
Javi: Thanks for inviting me. I'm looking forward to coming back and talking more about the Gothic remake.
Kai: Yes, that will be great. So, here's a bit of night music from the old camp. See you all in the next episode.
Javi: Bye bye, everybody.
Reinhard: Take care. Bye Bye.
Kai: Thank you for listening. That was... Chapter 2.