Xardas: Capitolo tre.
Reinhard: Benvenuti al Gothic 1 Remake Podcast.
Reinhard: Ci troviamo nelle terre selvagge appena fuori Campo Vecchio, seduti ad un falò.
Reinhard: E siamo qui per parlarvi di ciò che è successo ad Agosto riguardo Gothic 1 Remake.
Reinhard: Abbiamo avuto due momenti molto importanti.
Reinhard: Prima di tutto, c'è stato il rilascio del trailer di Campo Vecchio, che ha mostrato l'atmosfera e l'ambiente di Campo Vecchio.
Reinhard: Secondo, abbiamo una demo segreta che abbiamo portato con noi alla Gamescom e l'abbiamo mostrata a dei giornalisti e streamer selezionati.
Reinhard: E siamo qui per darvi qualche dettaglio e spiegazione di ciò che abbiamo mostrato.
Reinhard: Io sono Reinhard Pollice, sono il direttore di Alkimia Interactive. E sono qui con alcuni dei miei compagni che lavorano insieme a me a Gothic 1 Remake.
Reinhard: Prego presentatevi pure.
Joan: D'accordo. Beh, salve, mi chiamo Joan. Sono il Cinematic Designer qui in Alkimia.
Joan: Il mio ruolo consiste nel prendermi cura di tutte le parti cinematografiche presenti nel gioco.
Joan: Inoltre, anche i trailer che richiediamo per scopi di marketing.
Dani: Ok, io sono Dani Candil. Sono l'Art Director di Gothic Remake.
Kai: Hei, io sono Kai Rosenkranz, sono il compositore e sound designer.
Kai: Javi, vuoi continuare tu?
Javi: Si. È grandioso essere tornati qui. E grazie a tutti voi -la community- per tutti i feedback che avete fornito. È stato fantastico.
Timur: È il mio turno. Mi chiamo Timur (T-Moor), sono un grande fan di Gothic e community manager in Alkimia Interactive.
Reinhard: Grazie. Prima di tutto parliamo del trailer di Campo Vecchio. (Joan:Ok.) Cosa significa Campo Vecchio per te, Joan?
Joan: Per me, Campo Vecchio è la memoria più grande che hai del gioco originale, perché è il primo luogo in cui arrivi quando inizi a giocare.
Joan: E i personaggi hanno una personalità molto forte, e sono molto duri con te.
Joan: Ti senti davvero piccolo quando giochi, e penso che tutti ricordino ciò con nostalgia,
Joan: quelle conversazioni casuali tra NPC, i minatori che cercano di riparare le loro baracche tutto il tempo.
Joan: Non so... Campo Vecchio per me suona così.
Kai: Qualcuno ha detto suona? (Joan: Pare di si.)
Kai: Grazie, Joan. Monto gentile da parte tua. (Joan: Già.)
Reinhard: Quindi, cosa vuol dire per te Campo Vecchio, Dani?
Dani: Per me, Campo Vecchio è la parte più importante della colonia.
Dani: Voglio dire, in tutte le esperienze di Gothic è la parte più riconoscibile che c'è in termini di forme visive e caratteristiche, per me.
Dani: È una delle parti più difficili del gioco sui cui lavorare. È un intricato labirinto di capanne.
Dani: Intendo che... è interessante perché è uno scenario che viene riutilizzato. Nel senso, originariamente era una prigione, poi è diventato il castello di Gomez.
Dani: In quanto artista, questo è interessante perché mi permette la possibilità di lavorare con un alto livello di dettaglio
Dani: e con un alto livello di narrativa, sai, l'ambientazione che narra un sacco di cose su quel luogo.
Dani: E per me, in lontananza, voglio dire, ricorda che la torre di Campo Vecchio è la prima cosa che vedi.
Dani: È una delle cose più memorabili.
Reinhard: E come vi siete approcciati al trailer di Campo Vecchio?
Joan: Sapevamo sin dall'inizio che volevamo qualcosa di simile all'ultimo trailer,
Joan: il trailer della Vecchia Miniera, che aveva questa camera che volava tra l'ambiente per mostrare la vita in quel luogo.
Joan: Quindi volevamo lo stesso: mostrare la vita dentro Campo Vecchio, ma volevamo fare un passo in più.
Joan: Per questo pensavamo a nuovi modi sul come fare, no?  Così come tutti - in special modo, io (ride) -, amiamo il cinema.
Joan: Quindi cercavamo riferimenti li. Volevamo provare una camera ad inseguimento per il protagonista principale.
Joan: Una specie di piano sequenza, come nei film Goodfellas o Birdman, cose del genere.
Joan: Ma volevamo rimanere nello spirito di Gothic. Quindi non volevamo stravolgere tutto.
Joan: Insomma, questa è stata la nostra prima idea, cercare di creare un piano sequenza che seguiva il personaggio.
Joan: Dovevamo decidere il percorso - quali parti del campo volevamo mostrare, e alla fine abbiamo optato per la prima entrata,
Joan: poi qualcuna delle capanne dove di solito le guardie ti chiedono soldi nel gioco originale
Joan: e poi Snaf, il cibo ed infine l'arena.
Joan: Però in termine di tempo, questo percorso ha richiesto molto tempo.
Joan: Per camminare in questo percorso al personaggio ci vogliono 3 o 4 minuti.
Joan: Quindi il piano sequenza andava ottimizzato. (ride)
Joan: E alla fine abbiamo qualche taglio durante la scena, ma penso che funzionino bene.
Reinhard: Come avete trasportato l'idea in un qualcosa di visivo?
Joan: Allora, dopo aver avuto l'idea - abbiamo deciso di andare per il piano sequenza-,
Joan: avevamo bisogno di una cosa in più, ovvero una storia, un personaggio principale.
Joan: Avevamo qualcuno che comandasse questa telecamera.
Joan: Quindi dopo aver avuto l'idea, abbiamo creato una sceneggiatura su di un minatore
Joan: che ruba dei soldi a Bloodwyn, una delle guardie, che finisce per essere catturato da lui.
Reinhard: E poi cos'è successo?
Joan: Il prossimo passo è stato il creare uno storyboard, o meglio, abbiamo creato un'animazione - o previsualizzazione.
Joan: Mentre lavoravamo con Unreal, potevamo lavorare con i "Sequencer" direttamente dentro l'engine
Joan: e ciò ci ha permesso di avere delle animazioni fatte per altri scopi,
Joan: metterle assieme utilizzando dei controlli base dei rig ci ha permesso di modificare queste animazioni
Joan: in maniera facile. Così abbiamo creato il nostro storyboard animato. Perché l'ambientazione di Campo Vecchio era già finita quando stavamo creando il trailer.
Joan: Questo ci ha permesso di, beh, in pratica avevamo tutto.
Joan: Dovevamo solo assemblare quest'animazione e mostrarla agli animatori.
Joan: Era tutto ciò di cui avevamo bisogno.
Kai: Aha. Vuol dire che tutto ciò che si vede nel trailer avverrà anche nel gioco?
Reinhard: Allora, Campo Vecchio, come viene presentato nel trailer, è uguale a quello nelgioco.
Reinhard: Gli eventi che accadono possono accadere anche così, ma nel gioco avverranno dinamicamente. Nel trailer,
Reinhard: ovviamente, li abbiamo settati in sequenza uno dietro l'altro, così da avvenire convenientemente quando ci servivano.
Reinhard: E l'altra cosa che non sarà così nel gioco è la sequenza con la telecamera, che era stata creata specificatamente per il trailer.
Kai: Ok, capito. Grazie.
Reinhard: Quali sono le tue scene preferite del trailer?
Joan: Anche se le prime scene sono fighe, la mia preferita è quella con Snaf con il calderone e tutto il resto.
Joan: Perché la recitazione è molto divertente, abbiamo anche avuto un combattimento alla fine, quindi penso sia super completo.
Dani: Ok. Sai, quando abbiamo iniziato a discutere del trailer, voglio dire, abbiamo deciso, come dire, di mostrare lo spirito originale di Gothic.
Dani: La sensazione di essere a Campo Vecchio. Quando sia difficile vivere la, quando siano maleducati tutti.
Dani: Ma per me, il momento migliore, è quando appare Bloodwyn, sai, il tizio del pugno
Dani: che dice: ""Ok, mi devi pagare i tuoi debiti. Gomez ha bisogno del tuo minerale!"" Per me questo è un momento dove capisci che, ok, questo posto è pericoloso.
Dani: Dovresti tenere alla tua vita. Quindi penso che per me, sia questo il momento migliore per mostrare personaggi che si muovono ed interagiscono mentre due personaggi sono in un'interazione complicata.
Dani: Quindi, per me questa è la scena più memorabile del trailer.
Reinhard: (ride) Non è difficile creare un luogo con capanne COSÌ tanto simili tra loro?
Dani: Questa è una domanda divertente perché sai
Dani: Gothic ci offre la possibilità di lavorare manualmente su ognuna di quelle capanne.
Dani: Quindi, si, abbiamo dozzine di capanne, e posso assicurarti che ogni di quelle è unica, specifica e speciale.
Dani: Quindi, si, è una sfida perché dovresti offrire qualcosa di diverso per ognuna, ma allo stesso tempo devono sembrare integrate...
Dani: Tutte dovrebbero sembrare integrate nello stesso linguaggio visivo.
Dani: E... è una parte molto complicata del design dello spazio.
Dani: Dovrebbero sembrare, rumorose, labirintiche, intricare, dovrebbero sembrare sporche.
Dani: Quindi, si, è un'opportunità interessante per creare spazi labirintici, ma allo stesso tempo renderli unici.
Reinhard: Parlando di unicità, ogni faccia è unica, giusto?
Dani: Si, questa è una delle sfide più grandi del gioco. Cioè, le abbiamo create, tutte quante.
Dani: Cioè, ci lavoriamo da... Questo processo è iniziato due anni fa.
Dani: Abbiamo iniziato creando manualmente ogni personaggio e abbiamo lavorato assieme ai nostri
Dani: posso dirlo tranquillamente -dato che abbiamo speso così tante ore assieme a loro- fratelli e sorelle di Gate 21. Ci stanno aiutando molto.
Dani: Stiamo creando, stiamo provando, stiamo cercando di creare non so quanti personaggi abbiamo, forse 600 o giù di li, (Joan: Si!) tutti unici e speciali.
Dani: Quindi posiamo creare personaggi unici per poi unirli insieme e mischiarli per creare nuovi personaggi.
Dani: Quindi, stiamo - voglio dire - speriamo e proviamo con tutte le nostre forze per renderla l'esperienza che i fan di Gothic meritano.
Dani: Voglio dire, in Gothic, ricordo giocando l'originale, tutti, ogni personaggio sembrava unico, giusto? Unico! Quindi puntiamo a fare lo stesso.
Reinhard: Grandioso. Grazie per l'informazione. (Dani: Grazie.)
Reinhard: C'è qualcosa che cambieresti nel trailer se potessi tornare indietro?
Joan: Se avessi la possibilità, penso che cercherei di rivedere la prima parte del trailer. Forse ... ci sono troppe cose che accadono nello stesso momento. (Reinhard: Già.)
Joan: Potremmo provare un modo migliore d'introdurre il trailer, ma tutto sommato, penso che funzioni bene.
Kai: Oh si, assolutamente.
Kai: Anche se penso dovremmo affrontare il fatto che tutti parlino con accento londinese. Perché?
Reinhard: Abbiamo deciso di seguire l'atmosfera dura, quindi abbiamo scelto l'accento di Londra, ma non tutti hanno lo stesso accento.
Reinhard: Alcune persone vengono da posti diversi di Myrtana e quindi parlando differentemente, come Diego, che ha un accento molto diverso e non quello londinese.
Reinhard: Direi che: si, Campo Vecchio suonerà più rozzo e sembrerà molto londinese, ma tutto sommato non sarà neanche più del 50%. (Kai: Ok, capito.)
Kai: Grazie per la chiarificazione.
Reinhard: D'accordo. Dato che siamo seduti ad un falò, abbiamo ovviamente bisogno di qualcosa da mangiare.
Reinhard: Mi mangerò un poke di Squalo di palude. Cosa posso servirvi?
Timur: Grazie, Reinhard.
Kai: Si, grazie. Ma in realtà, puoi continuare a parlare, prenderò io gli ordini e preparerò tutto .(Reinhard: Grazie.)
Kai: Timur, cosa scegli?
Timur: Credo che il mio preferito sia la bistecca di saprofago arrosto di Bartholos con salsa barbecue.
Timur: E da bere, vorrei la vodka del Signore del Riso.
Kai: D'accordo, vodka del Signore del Riso. Perfetto! Allora Javi, cosa vuoi?
Javi: Saprofago arrosto e una bottiglia di birra.
Kai: Perfetto, prenderò la stessa cosa! Dani?
Dani: Beh, Paella di scarafaggio con lo speciale del Signore del Riso. Sarebbe perfetto.
Kai: Un'altra dal Signore del Riso. D'accordo! Joan, è il tuo turno.
Joan: Che mi dici del filetto grigliato di Squalo di palude? S'il vous plaît.
Kai: Mais oui, bien sûr! E da bere?
Joan: Si, da bere magari un succo vegetale di quello che possiamo trovare qua.
Kai: Ok. In arrivo.
Reinhard: Ora, parliamo del prologo di Nyras, che è stata la demo che avete mostrato alla stampa e agli streamers alla Gamescom.
Kai: Yeah, actually, I think that needs some more introduction. (Reinhard: Yes.) So what is the ... What is it?
Reinhard: So, the Nyras Prolog is really a slice of the game that contains almost all elements in a close to final form, and it features not the nameless hero, but the character called Nyras.
Reinhard: And we chose this because the start of the game is not really something that has a big - like - progression curve, because it expects you to go to the Old Camp and do some talking there.
Reinhard: Our goal was that within 30 minutes you get to see every element of the game and we could achieve this with this setup. (Kai: Yeah, that makes a lot of sense.)
Kai: The first food's ready. Ehm, Paella was for you, Dani, right? (Dani: Exactly, yes!)
Kai: There you go. (Dani: Thanks.) Reinhard, why did we choose Nyras for the prolog?
Reinhard: We had obviously several options because before the Nameless Hero gets sent into the colony, obviously other characters get sent into the colony.
Reinhard: (Kai talking to others in the background, giving out food and drinks.) Reinhard: And so it was a guy named Nyras that later turned his attention to the swamp and plays a very important part later down the road in the game.
Kai: Cool. Thank you. Here's your meal. (Reinhard: Thanks.) That should be everything.
Reinhard: So what was the main goal of the Nyras Prolog and how did we start?
Javi: Well, I think our main goal was to show all the progress of the game and a little bit how the game has changed from the PT - from the playable teaser.
Javi: So we have a lot of things to show, and one of the more important things that we wanted to show was the Exchange Zone at the end, because it changed a lot from the previous version we had done. This limit of the level, the space, and we build from there.
Javi: There are a lot of things that we want to show there.
Javi: Well, we can talk about all the mechanics or systems.
Javi: I don't know which one do you want to start talking about?
Reinhard: I think we should start exactly with that. The Exchange Zone.
Reinhard: So is it a completely new exchange zone?
Javi: Well, it's pretty much the same.
Javi: I think all the players will recognize it. It's the place they imagine, like a new version but the same place.
Javi: (Dani: Yeah.) We want to build from the original. We have created this Exchange Zone where - well - in the prolog Whistler and Diego were there. And we keep most of the rhythm of the level.
Javi: We keep the abandoned mine entrance, the bridge...
Javi: Well, I think all the players will recognize it perfectly. (Dani: Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.)
Javi: Yeah, we have these, these different areas that we work with. Because we have also the top area where - you know - all the players remember there was there Goblin in there.
Javi: We have also the tree with the Scavengers and... Yeah!
Javi: From our level perspective we keep the same and we want to show it and create a story for the beginning of any prisoner when they go inside the colony.
Reinhard: Cool. So what was the process?
Javi: Well, from the level perspective, what we create is taking the original, we create a blockout and we try to keep as much as possible (true) to the original one.
Javi: But also we want to improve it, giving these areas more... more deepness and more flavor for what they are, really.
Javi: And then we talk with the art team when we have this blockout to start working on the - okay - the decoration, the framing, more stuff in a in a visual way.
Javi: Also we..., when we are doing these blockouts, we also thought about the
Javi: the creatures who are there. Because for us it's very important
Javi: to create this habitat for the creatures. Like where they live, where they sleep, where they eat,
Javi: how is their daily routine also for the creatures? Because at the end
Javi: they are living creatures also. And, and yeah, and also one of the of the important things for for this
Javi: prolog is to create this pacing for the quests. But it's also very important for us, for when we create a space, we have also in mind the quest that will be there and... Yeah, that's our process.
Javi: We create this, we place the people, we try it, we iterate, we talk with the art team, they create awesome visuals for these spaces.
Javi: And yeah, it's something like... We start from from the blockout and from there we continue with, with all these things.
Dani: Yeah. The cool thing is that when we start preparing the blockout phase,
Dani: I mean, we meet together with the designers, with the level designers, so we can share the same vision
Dani: about how this space should be explored, how this a space should look and feel.
Dani: So when they give the blockout to us, we are basically working on the same page.
Dani: So we start our process of, you know, searching for believable environments.
Dani: I mean, we should transform this blockout into believable environments, into believable constructions.
Dani: So we'll start, you know, drawing and sketching and searching for references.
Dani: It's super important to always search for realistic references.
Dani: And we start playing with materials and trying to create the right sensation, the right mood, the right structures.
Dani: And sometimes we go a little overboard with the details.
Dani: But in general, the cool thing is that here we work together as a great team. We share the same vision.
Dani: So basically when we start decorating, we already know how this should end up looking.
Reinhard: That's great. Thanks for the insight.
Reinhard: The changed Exchange Zone does have a new fireplace right? (Javi: Right.)
Javi: This fire point in the Exchange Zone that we placed there for the players to be able to cook some recipes.
Javi: There are a lot of creatures in the Exchange Zone that give you meat.
Javi: Like the Scavengers and the Molerats also.
Javi: But this is one of our bases. Because we want the player to get this meat and prepare the recipes, the dishes.
Javi: And it's a way to survive in the wildlands.
Javi: Also we are having a lot of interest in developing better the hunting skills because it's something
Javi: that we think is important for the game because at the end you are in the wildlands, you need to survive.
Javi: You need to get these material from the creatures.
Javi: And for us, it's very, very important to give this feeling of adventure of... Okay, you have to get prepared with this.
Javi: And we will use these materials for many kinds of crafting because we will have not just cooking, we will have more crafting there.
Javi: Yeah, it's something important for us and we will give this a little bit more and land
Javi: because at the end you can prepare different dishes with different materials.
Kai: And I got to say: The way it is executed in the Nyras Prolog, the cooking mechanic, already works very well. (Javi: Yes.)
Kai: Why did we choose the Exchange Zone for the demo ground?
Reinhard: Using the exchange zone as the scenery for the Prolog was a natural choice because it can
Reinhard: very well be separated from the rest of the world and doesn't need to get borders everywhere.
Reinhard: It already has very natural borders, almost anywhere other than in the mountain path.
Reinhard: So we only had to find an explanation of why this path is blocked. (Kai: And what is that explanation?)
Reinhard: So, the setup was that the rockslide happened and rocks were basically blocking the way down.
Reinhard: And since there were people kind of like busy with some dealings in there, they are now trapped in this environment.
Kai: Yeah, yeah, I guess that works.
Reinhard: Joan, you were an important part of that.
Reinhard: You contributed the concept of the cinematic camera system.
Joan: Yeah. Well, I think the challenge for the cinematic dialogs that we wanted to have was specially... Normally in cinema,
Joan: when you have a shot-by-shot situation, you also have an editing, right?
Joan: (Kai: Yes.) An editing that has some sense and reasons inside the cinematic rules that we all know.
Joan: So for us, this was the main challenge because we wanted to have
Joan: a lot of diferent cameras as you can experience in cinema, not just two or three.
Joan: And at the end this was difficult to achieve, even though for the game we are going to have it!
Joan: But for the demo we did some tests and finally to achieve the quality that we wanted to achieve,
Joan: we needed to cut the idea and we have have, I think, two or three cameras for the demo.
Joan: But also when we were doing our research, looking into other third person RPG games for inspiration,
Joan: we noticed that maybe the most important thing for... for the dialog scenes to look cinematic was the light.
Dani: Exactly. Yes.
Joan: We discovered that in most of these games add new lights when the dialog starts.
Joan: And for us, this was key. So that was another thing that we needed to add
Joan: on top of the cameras in order to achieve a super nice cinematic dialogs.
Joan: So now we are working hard on that.
Joan: We are designing our systems in order to achieve this. And yeah, I hope you like it in the final game.
Reinhard: Yes! So the Nyras demo contains a slice of everything - and for the first time also the UI, right?
Javi: Right! And for us is very important to show it. Because one of the most important things
Javi: from Gothic is immersion, and we want to keep the immersion very clear.
Javi: We don't want to have these full screen menus that doesn't allow to to continue playing.
Javi: Instead, checking your inventory is part of the game.
Javi: You cannot just pause the game and check what you have. It's in the middle of the game. You can do it close to an enemy,
Javi: but it's on your own risk. And also, well - we give a review to it.
Javi: But yeah, we have this in mind. That's something very important from the original.
Javi: Like, we don't want to have a lot of numbers or text or health bars in the middle of the screens.
Javi: We want to keep it as clean as possible and it's something that I want to show in the prolog.
Kai: That's great. One thing we haven't yet talked about is combat!
Kai: The Nyras Prolog also had - like - a first iteration of the new combat system. (Javi: Yes, exactly.)
Reinhard: So how did you get the combat to work?
Javi: Yeah. For the combat, what's also something very important for us to show to the audience
Javi: was the gestures, the postures for the combat, the stance.
Javi: I mean, like... we want the player to know that at the beginning it would be rough!
Javi: You would not be a master with the sword or even with the pickaxe,
Javi: because one of the first weapons you can find in the Exchange Zone is a pickaxe.
Javi: So for us it's a challenge to make this, but I think we accomplish it.
Javi: Because the player can start fighting,
Javi: they movement is not feeling as good as you think, because you are watching a non-specialist warrior.
Javi: You're watching a... just a prisoner in the colony. And also, in the prolog
Javi: we work to have this combat versus Kirgo and you can learn combat from him and he will teach you...
Javi: Okay, this is how you can use a one-handed weapon and then you evolve as a... as a fighter.
Javi: And yeah, these's a lot of things, because also we have these special movesets for different kinds of weapons.
Javi: It's not the same for a mace, a sword, an axe.
Javi: And of course, for all (two weapons) ... two-handed weapons.
Javi: So we wanted to show all these evolutions for all these kinds of weapons.
Javi: And it's a challenge, but I think it feels really, really good at the hands
Javi: when you are a beginner with a weapon and you...
Javi: and you start to know how to fight. Because we want to keep the game
Javi: as relying on the ability of the player, but also it's an RPG.
Javi: So you have to learn how to use a weapon. (Kai: Yeah.)
Kai: And so many people out there wanted to see the new combat system in action.
Kai: Why haven't we shown any gameplay to the public audience yet?
Reinhard: So we showed some screenshots of what we presented.
Reinhard: They were 1-to-1 from this prolog.
Reinhard: There are some things where we didn't achieve the quality that we wanted to achieve or
Reinhard: contained some bugs or unpolished things, and we don't want to overshadow the public opinion by that.
Reinhard: So we chose to not release any footage to the public. But we'll have later down the road a real gameplay reveal
Reinhard: where people get to see unedited gameplay of the Gothic 1 Remake.
Dani: So, Reinhard, what is going to happen with the Nyras Prolog?
Reinhard: So, we haven't really decided what will happen with the Nyras Prolog.
Reinhard: We have this done now.
Reinhard: We're working on that there's some things will be improved because we improve them for the game anyways.
Reinhard: There are several options. One could be a public release, and one could actually be... well...
Reinhard: as a kind of like a special data sample that is living in the game and can be accessed somehow.
Kai: Okay, you're making a big secret out of it.
Reinhard: Yeah, it's cool. And I don't like to make big promises, you know me! (Kai: Fair enough.)
Kai: Better this way than the other way around.
Reinhard: Yeah. Over the history of the Gothic franchise, we know how big promises end, right?
Everyone: Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. Very true.
Kai: Alright, so... almost half an hour. What else do we have to talk about?
Timur: I have some questions from our community. (Kai: Oh yeah, yeah. Great!) Let's go through some of them.
Kai: Okay. Sounds good.
Timur: So, the question with the most upvotes was from a user with the nickname Shaolyn:
Timur: ""Will the game have mod support for the modding community to create them easily and for community content to be added over the years? And will there be a marvin mode?"" (submitted by Shaolyn)
Reinhard: So mod support is actually something really important to us.
Reinhard: We understand there's a big community creating mods since many, many years.
Reinhard: In fact, around 20 years ago I used to create my own mods for gothic, but we have some limitation to fight with.
Reinhard: We work with Unreal Engine and Unreal Engine is not the best engine for modding.
Reinhard: But anyways, we found a pretty cool way where we can expose something like a scripting language to players
Reinhard: and they can just toy around with that.
Reinhard: About the marvin mode: Yeah, I mean there are some sort of debug commands. We'll see.
Timur: Yeah. Thank you, Shaolyn, for your question.
Timur: And the second question is from a very active Discord member: Asnen.
Timur: And the question is:""What motivated the significant changes in the appearance of monsters in the Gothic Remake in comparison to the original in terms of your art direction choices?"". Asnen, thank you for your question.
Timur: Oh, maybe this question is for you, Dani.
Dani: Well, that's a tricky question. And of course there's not a simple answer to that.
Dani: But when you are redesigning creatures, monsters that were designed more than 20 years ago,
Dani: you are facing some esthetic decisions, technical limitations that maybe were valid then,
Dani: but maybe they can feel a little outdated now.
Dani: This is one part of the answer: the evolution of the esthetics and technique,
Dani: the way we can render creatures now, technically and artistically
Dani: that wasn't possible back then gives you the opportunity
Dani: to go deep into the original designs and make them evolve and going the extra mile.
Dani: But having said that, we designed the creatures trying to find the sweet spot between three main vectors:
Dani: 1: The principles of evolutionary biology, especially thinking in the adaptations.
Dani: I mean - by""adaptations"" I mean those features that have evolved in the species
Dani: over time in response to specific environmental pressures
Dani: that provide some functional advantage for them. 2: Adding to that mix a controlled amount of fantasy.
Dani: So essentially the creatures should feel believable,
Dani: believable inside the world of Gothic, that in essence is a dark medieval tale.
Dani: And 3: Those two previous vectors should go toe to toe with the original idea behind the original designs.
Dani: So we can change a little the look of a creature,
Dani: but once you see it moving and behaving in a world, we are confident you will recognize it immediately.
Timur: Thanks, Dani.
Timur: So the question number three is from Jasoon.
Timur: ""How much do you plan to expand the plot on the Nameless One's four friends: Diego, Milten, Gorn and Lester? For example, their past, their own side quests, greater involvement in the story."" (submitted by Jasoon)
Reinhard: That's a really good question.
Reinhard: So for us, the Four Friends is some of the lasting moments of the Gothic series, I think.
Reinhard: But in fact it didn't receive such a proper introduction.
Reinhard: So this is definitely something that we want to provide something better.
Reinhard: And a good moment where all four of them with the hero are together and having to solve something.
Reinhard: And besides that, I mean, yes, there will be a more in-depth background stories for those four friends.
Timur: Thanks, Reinhard, and thanks Jasoon for your question.
Timur: And the last question is from user Xardosh.
Timur: ""Do we have a way to customize the nameless hero like a head shave or tattoos, for example, after joining the sect camp?"" (submitted by Xardosh)
Kai: I think I can answer this one. (Timur: Xardosh, thank you for your question!) Yeah, thank you.
Kai: So this one is very easy to answer because it's a no.
Kai: There's no such thing as customization for the Nameless Hero planned.
Timur: Yeah. Thanks everyone, for sending your questions.
Timur: We will try to answer the rest of them in later episodes.
Reinhard: Okay, let's wrap it up. That's it.
Reinhard: Thanks for joining us on this campfire chat.
Reinhard: We hope we gave you some additional insights into how we created the Nyras Prolog and the Old Camp trailer.
Reinhard: We look forward to have you on the next regular episode of the Gothic 1 Remake Podcast and bring you some more news about Gothic.